Expect the incredible.
The Incredibles is a action, adventure, animation film directed by Brad Bird.
Bob Parr has given up his superhero days to log in time as an insurance adjuster and
raise his three children with his formerly heroic wife in suburbia.
But when he receives a mysterious assignment,
it's time to get back into costume.
Bob Parr / Mr. Incredible (voice), played by Craig T. Nelson.
Helen Parr / Elastigirl (voice), played by Holly Hunter.
Violet Parr (voice), played by Sarah Vowell.
Dashiell 'Dash' Parr (voice), played by Spencer Fox.
Buddy Pine / Syndrome (voice), played by Jason Lee.
Lucius Best / Frozone (voice), played by Samuel L. Jackson.
The Incredibles is a 2004 American animated superhero film produced
by Pixar Animation Studios for Walt Disney Pictures.
Written and directed by Brad Bird, it stars the voices of Craig T.
Nelson, Holly Hunter, Sarah Vowell, Spencer Fox, Jason Lee, Samuel L.
Jackson, and Elizabeth Peña.
Set in a retro-futuristic version of the 1960s, the film follows Bob and
Helen Parr, a superhero couple respectively known as Mr.
Incredible and Elastigirl, who hide their powers in accordance with a government mandate that
outlawed superheroes, and attempt to live a quiet suburban life with their three children.
However, Bob's desire to help people draws the entire family into
a confrontation with a vengeful fan-turned-foe.
Bird, who was Pixar's first outside director, developed the film as an extension of the
1960s comic books and spy films from his boyhood and personal family life.
He pitched the film to Pixar after Warner Bros.' box office disappointment of his first feature, The
Iron Giant (1999), and carried over much of its staff to develop The Incredibles.
The animation team was tasked with animating an all-human cast, which required creating new
technology to animate detailed human anatomy, clothing, and realistic skin and hair.
Michael Giacchino composed the film's orchestral score.
The Incredibles debuted at the El Capitan Theatre on October 24, 2004, and
was released in theaters in the United States on November 5.
It earned $632 million worldwide, finishing its theatrical run
as the fourth-highest-grossing film of 2004.
The Incredibles received widespread acclaim from critics, with praise for its animation,
screenplay, voice acting, action sequences, sound design, humor, and music.
The film won Best Animated Feature and Best Sound Editing at the 77th Academy Awards, with two additional nominations
for Best Original Screenplay and Best Sound Mixing, as well as the Annie Award for Best Animated Feature.
It was the first entirely animated film to win the Hugo
Award for Best Dramatic Presentation.
A sequel, Incredibles 2, was released in June 2018,
while a third film is in development.
The film explores themes of hero, secret identity,
superhero, villain, family relationships.